Nicholas Brink

Salhouse Road, Rackheath, Norwich, NR13 6PD Phone: 07918145194 | Email: nicbrink@gmail.com| LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/nickbrink

Summary

An accountant with a background in education and publishing with a view of moving over to software development. A critical thinker with strong analytical skills with the ability to make well thought out decisions with a good understanding of accounting principles. Good organizational skills developed in a variety of deadline orientated situations with the ability to work calmly and effectively under pressure. Connect with people at all levels, easily making good working relationships. Good presentation skills combining sound analytical research and clear verbal explanation. Ability to work proactively within a team and on own initiative. Ability to handle difficult customers in a calm and tactful manner

Education

University of South Africa (UNISA) 2012

Bachelor of Commerce Degree – Finance

Cape Peninsula University of Technology 2004

Marketing Diploma

Experience

Royalty Accountant
Welbeck Publishing
2014 - Present
London, UK

- Account/bank reconciliation's
- Managing over 6000 titles and royalty statements
- Receiving new contracts, updating, maintaining databases and formulating royalty statements
- Calculating and sending periodical royalty statements to various stakeholders
- Building and maintaining internal relationships with internal editorial staff, authors and licensors
- Granting permissions and rights to various external organizations for various content usages
- Royalty queries, working independently without supervision

Assistant Management Accountant Welbeck Publishing

2016 - 2021 London, UK

- Assist in the preparation of monthly management accounts
- Control of accruals & prepayments
- Budget variance analysis
- Reconciling distributor accounts
- Assistance in preparation of annual statutory accounts
- Reviewing title profitability

Group Accountant2012 - 2014 ITR Africa Johannesburg, South Africa

- Account/bank reconciliation's
- Analyzing and investigating annual and monthly financial accounts
- Payroll administration
- Processing of payments
- Preparation of financial statements and reports of the group on a monthly basis and report to shareholders
- Preparation and monthly submission of VAT, PAYE to SARS
- Assist the directors with budgets and forecasts
- Preparation and coordination of the audit process
- Maintenance of the fixed asset registers
- Managing a group of 12 debtors, creditors clerks in 4 branches

Finance and Admin Manager Aylesford International

January 2009 – September 2012 Cape Town, South Africa

- Invoicing, collection and monthly reporting on outstanding debtors
- Commission calculations

- Account/bank reconciliation's
- Maintenance of the fixed asset registers
- Prepare financial statements and reports
- Assist the directors with budgets and forecasts
- Payroll administration
- Processing of payments for creditors and landlords
- Preparation and coordination of the audit process
- Perform general office duties and administrative tasks
- Design of all company advertising (business cards, corporate brochures and newspaper adverts)
- Maintenance and upgrade of company websites
- Customer queries related to payments and rental queries
- In charge of training agents on the use of loading properties on backend of websites, database management (Access), and other computer related queries.

Accountant and Director Evelyn Brink Artist Management

2012 - 2017

Cape Town, South Africa

- Invoicing, collection and monthly reporting on outstanding debtors
- Account/bank reconciliation's
- Payroll administration
- Processing of payments
- Preparation and monthly submission of VAT, PAYE to SARS
- Website development and maintenance

Secondary School Teacher: Mathematics & Business Economics Bayside High School

2006 - 2009

Hout Bay, South Africa

- Teaching classes and assessing students' progress and performance
- Planning and preparing lessons, setting papers and preparing report cards
- Providing constructive feedback and guidance to students experiencing educational or personal challenges
- Maintaining order and discipline in the classroom
- Communicating with parents, teachers and other professionals
- Employing a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximize individual learning within a group environment
- Utilizing computer resources, including educational software and the Internet, to promote interactive learning

Skills

- Sage, Pastel Accounting, Kerridge, SAP
- Microsoft Office (Access, Excel (Advanced), Outlook, PowerPoint, Word)
- Corel Draw
- Adobe Photoshop
- Software: HTML, CSS, Java, Bootstrap